KENDRA MORRIS

Software Developer

(804)332-3498 | Kendranmorris@gmail.com | Frisco, TX | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-morris/ | https://github.com/kmorr102 | https://moonlit-mermaid-59cc47.netlifv.app/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Fullstack Developer with over a decade of experience in healthcare, prior experience with marketing, and a growing curiosity for software development! I have an interest in complex problem-solving, and have a strong analytical mindset. I am actively seeking a role that fosters continuous growth and innovation!

EDUCATION

Certificate|Fullstack Academy Web Development Bootcamp| Oct 2023

Masters of Science Kinesiology|University of North Texas |May 2022

Bachelors of Science in Exercise Science|University of North Carolina at Charlotte| May 2019

Technical Skills: API, coding, Database Design, Express.js, Github, HTML/CSS, Insomnia, Javascript, JSON, Node.js, Postbird, PostgreSQL, Software Development Life Cycle, SQL, Visual Studio Code

Soft Skills: Attention To Detail, Collaboration, communication skills, context switching, Energetic, Interpersonal Skills, Leadership, Organized, planning, Quick Learner, Self-starter, Teamwork, Time management, troubleshooting, verbal communication skills

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Girl Dinner

Developer

September 2023 - October 2023

https://github.com/kmorr102/Girl-Dinner

- Designed a review site for users to review and interact with local restaurants
- Leveraged the power of PostgreSQL to create a robust backend system that seamlessly integrated with our frontend website
- Designed and implemented a RESTful API using PostgreSQL as the database management system
- Created endpoints that enabled users to perform essential CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the data
- Collaborated within a cross-functional team in an Agile environment throughout the entirety of the project
- Documented all active and completed task on a weekly basis using a project board

Stranger's Things

Developer

August 2023

https://github.com/kmorr102/strangers-things

- Designed and implemented a user-friendly website facilitating seamless transactions for buying and selling personal items
- Utilized React, React Toastify, CSS, and HTML to create an intuitive, visually appealing interface
- Implemented authentication and security by incorporating JWTs, enhancing user data protection
- Employed Insomnia for thorough API testing and validation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lab Coordinator | Intuitive Health: Legacy ER and Urgent Care | Frisco, Texas

July 2023 - Present

- Streamline lab operations by coordinating equipment maintenance and inventory to meet fluctuating patient demands within budget.
- Manages proficiency testing for 15 employees, resulting in improved reporting accuracy and identification of training needs
- Implements quality control standards and improved overall accuracy of manual lab test to 98%
- Coordination of laboratory equipment maintenance, and laboratory supply inventory to meet demands of a fluctuating patient census
- Completion of monthly deliverables

Emergency Room Technician | Intuitive Health: Legacy ER and Urgent Care | Frisco, Texas

September 2022 - Present

- Maintains a high level of patient satisfaction through comprehensive care under physician orders
- Increases patient satisfaction scores through timely treatment, and decreased door to door times below 60 minutes
- Reduces documentation errors by 10% through thorough documentation of patient encounters with the EMR system

• Use of language interpretation tools like video remote interpretation(VRI) and over the phone interpretation(OPI)

Fitness Graduate Assistant|UNT Recreation Sports| Denton, Texas

August 2020 - May 2022

- Designed effective marketing strategies that resulted in 20% increase in student engagement with the use of social media marketing, video marketing as well as email marketing
- Supervised 65+ student staff, maximizing facility operations and elevating patron satisfaction
- Implemented data analytic strategies to increase program engagement, resulting in more efficient use of resources and improved program planning initiatives
- Acted as a mentor to prospective personal trainer and group fitness students
- Collaborated with marketing teams to maintain social media presence through content management and marketing components
- Analyzed patron participant data and designed charts, graphs, and other illustrations to present program success and promote future program planning

HOBBIES: DIY crafts, Furniture Flipping, Dog training, Travel